What I'm going to talk about now is spotting your print.
Now spotting your print is when you have a print that you've made and there are pieces of dust or hair, that you do not want people to see in your print.
Now in the best world, you were able to get off the dust and hair with your negative cleaner or with your anti-static cloth, but as we all know things happen, sometimes there is even dust in the enlarger, sometimes there's dust on the paper when you took it out of the box who knows.
But regardless, there's usually a little bit of spots in everybody's print and there's a couple of different ways that you can make it so they're not so noticeable.
This way is called spotting and what this is, is it's a name called Spot-tone and I have a brush.
I'm going to talk about now is the brush.
This is a double zero delta.
I'll either use a double zero or a triple zero sable brush.
These brushes can range from seven dollars upwards to thirty or forty dollars.
In some ways the more expensive brush you have, the easier it is to spot.
You always want to make sure you have something of a decent brush and it really shouldn't, it really a double zero or a triple zero is the absolute best kind of brush to use.